Vuli Russell Willis

Portfolio: https://vulirussell.io
Github: https://github.com/vuli-russell/

I am a trainee software developer, having completed a 12 week intensive software development course with _nology. My previous experience includes a masters degree in chemical engineering and working as a process engineer for several years, where I realised that the aspects of my job that interested me the most were the parts involving any coding, leading me to commit to becoming a software developer.

When not locked down, I enjoy playing football and squash, and am a keen (if not yet very proficient) kite surfer.

Technical Skills

html, css, javascript, nodejs, react, bootstrap, express, firebase, sass, jest/enzyme, mongodb, git/github

Education

University of Bath

MEng (Hons) Chemical Engineering (5 year sandwich) 2013-2018 Upper second class honours

Durham Johnston Comprehensive School, Durham City, Durham

A-Levels: Chemistry A*, Physics A, Maths A, Biology B

AS-Level: Economics A

Experience

Sep. 2020– Nov. 2020 Trainee Software Developer - _nology, Bristol

database.

Undertook a 12 week software development course at _nology in order to gain the skill set to transition into a software development career.. This course focussed on web development, and included a 5 week project with a real world client, building a website for tracking operations and processes on mines, aimed at the South African mining industry. For this project I worked as part of an agile team, pair programming and delivering weekly builds of the project to the client.

On this project I worked on both the front end and integration with a firestore

Sep. 2018 – Sep. 2020

Process Engineer - A-Gas UK, Bristol

Responsible for leading projects for the development of new process equipment, from preliminary design through to commissioning and handover to operations. I have spent time supporting other members of the team to complete calculations and produce technical drawings to ensure that projects are completed on time. I work with operations staff to resolve process issues on production equipment. Through AGas I have been a mentor in the EES scheme, working with 6th Form students to find a solution to a real world engineering problem.

Sep. 2016 - Aug. 2017

Junior Process Engineer - A-Gas UK, Bristol

As part of my degree I spent a year working in Industry. My role was to assist with design, construction and commissioning of new process equipment at the AGas UK site. Additionally I was responsible for some smaller projects, such as safety checks and insurance inspections of existing equipment. As a result of this work I was offered a graduate role at the business.

Sep. 2012 - Aug. 2013

AMEC Environmental Consultancy Services, Newcastle upon Tyne I completed a year of work experience as part of the Year in Industry programme. I was responsible for thorough and accurate data collation, mostly relating to groundwater in East Anglia for the Environment Agency. I produced figures for reports, and set up and ran computer models.